<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on</title><link>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:30:05 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>基于生物运动的社交焦虑者情绪加工与社会意图理解负向偏差机制</title><link>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2023-zh-biomotion/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:30:05 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2023-zh-biomotion/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>社交焦虑者在情绪加工和社会意图理解方面均可能存在异常, 以负向认知偏差为代表, 但目前尚缺乏针对社交焦虑的情绪与社会意图理解共性机制的研究和临床预测模型。本项目计划综合运用行为实验、功能磁共振成像和计算建模, 基于情绪识别与社会意图推理的生物运动范式, 并结合面部表情识别任务, 系统考察社交焦虑者在情绪加工和社会意图加工中的负向认知偏差机制, 并构建社交焦虑症状的预测模型, 检验精神疾病背后的多维数据关联, 以及多维数据对社交焦虑临床症状的客观分类和预测的作用。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>关键词&lt;/strong> 情绪识别, 社交焦虑, 社会意图理解, 生物运动, 脑影像, 认知计算&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>成人社交焦虑问卷中文版的效度和信度评价</title><link>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2024-zh-questionnaire-sad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:29:35 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2024-zh-questionnaire-sad/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>目的：检验成人社交焦虑问卷中文版(CSAQ-A)的效度和信度。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>方法：选取555名成人 [年龄18—60岁，平均(29±8)岁]完成CSAQ-A。采用Liebowitz社交焦虑量表(LSAS)、简版惧怕否定评价量表(BFNE)、宾州忧虑问卷(PSWQ)、特质焦虑量表(STAI—T)、贝克抑郁量表第二版(BDIII)为效标工具。间隔4周后143名成人完成重测。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>结果：5因子结构的拟合指数良好(&lt;em>x^2/df&lt;/em>=3.06，CFI =0.92，TLI=0.91，RMSEA=0.06，SRMR=0.05)；CSAQ·A得分与LSAS、BFNE、PSWQ、STAI—T、 BDI-II得分均呈正相关(ICC=0.40～0.67，均&lt;em>p&lt;/em>&amp;lt;0.001)。CSAQ—A总量表的Cronbach Ot系数为0.96，重 测信度为0.80。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>结论：成人社交焦虑问卷中文版评估成年人群社交焦虑症状的效度和信度良好。&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Revisiting Resting-State Functional Connectivity of the Amygdala and Subgenual Anterior Cingulate Cortex in Adolescents and Adults With Depression</title><link>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2024-brain-mdd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:29:18 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2024-brain-mdd/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;h6 id="background">BACKGROUND&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>Adolescent depression is a growing public health concern, and neuroimaging offers a promising approach to its pathology. We focused on the functional connectivity of the amygdala and subgenual anterior cingulate cortex (sgACC), which is theoretically important in major depressive disorder (MDD), but empirical evidence has remained inconsistent. This discrepancy is likely due to the limited statistical power of small sample sizes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h6 id="methods">METHODS&lt;/h6>
&lt;p>We rigorously examined sgACC-amygdala connectivity in adolescents and adults with depression using data from the Healthy Brain Network (n = 321; 170 female), the ABCD (Adolescent Brain Cognitive Development) Study (n = 141; 56 female), the Boston Adolescent Neuroimaging of Depression and Anxiety study (n = 108; 75 female), and the REST-meta-MDD project (n = 1436; 880 female). Linear mixed models, Bayesian factor analyses, and meta-analysis were used to assess connectivity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Psychodynamic profiles of major depressive disorder and generalized anxiety disorder in China</title><link>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2024-psychodynamic-mdd-gad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 11:29:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://yuxiwang670.github.io/publication/articles/article2024-psychodynamic-mdd-gad/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Traditional clinical diagnoses relying on symptoms may overlook latent factors that illuminate mechanisms and potentially guide treatment. The Operationalized Psychodynamic Diagnosis (OPD) system may compensate for symptom-based diagnosis by measuring psychodynamic profiles underlying mental disorders through conflicts and structure axes. However, OPD has not been widely adopted in China, and it remains unclear whether OPD can be used as an effective approach to distinguish between depression and anxiety. The current study aims to adopt the OPD system to investigate the psychodynamic profiles of major depressive disorder (MDD) and generalized anxiety disorder (GAD) in China, targeting patients with “pure” symptoms without comorbidity. We recruited 42 MDD patients, 32 GAD patients, and 31 healthy controls (HC), and assessed their self-report depression and anxiety symptoms, along with their underlying psychodynamic profiles through OPD interviews. Overall, both MDD and GAD patients showed more prominent conflict issues and lower levels of structure than HC. The MDD and GAD groups yielded different conflict profiles and conflict processing modes when processing their second conflicts. Importantly, the multi-dimensional psychodynamic profiles achieved machine learning classification of clinical groups with an accuracy of 0.84, supporting successful distinction of MDD and GAD patients.In conclusion,the OPD demonstrated sensitivity in revealing distinct psychodynamic profiles underlying “pure” depression and anxiety clinical populations in China. This work calls for future incorporation of OPD as a tool to investigate psychodynamic formulations underlying mental disorders, compensating for traditional symptom-based diagnostic approaches to guide precise individualized interventions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>